Okay, so now that our LoRaWAN Server is ready, we'll be able to configure our Private Network, and for
that we'll use exactly the same four steps that we've explained earlier.
The first step is the Gateway configuration.
It tells the Gateway how to reach the Network Server.
The second step is the Gateway registration, because only a registered Gateway is allowed to talk to
the Network Server.
And for the third step, we're going to register our end-device on the Network Server.
I'm going to do it quickly because we've done it already with TTN, which is the community edition of
The Things Stack.
And it's exactly the same process.
And finally, the fourth step is the device configuration.
All right.
Let's start with the first step, the Gateway registration.
Our The Things Stack Server listens on Port 1700.
We could also use Basic Station packet forwarder, but again, I will do it in the easy way and keep
the UDP Semtech packet forwarder for this demonstration.
As we said earlier, the service in charge of this is called the Gateway Server.
So in our case we need to configure the Gateway to send its LoRaWAN data to the address
tts.univ-lorawan.fr on Port 1700. Depending on the Gateway we have,
there are several options to configure it.
In my case, in the gateway configuration web page, I change the destination address.
I save the settings and that's it.
First step is done.
Okay, but just before leaving this configuration page, I'm just going to copy the Gateway EUI because
I will need it in a few seconds for the Gateway Registration.
Now I go back on The Things Stack Server for the second step.
I'm going to register my Gateway.
We've done it already, so please go back on the corresponding video to see the process in detail.
From the console we go on the Gateway section.
We hit the register Gateway button and we enter a new page asking us the Gateway EUI and frequency plan.
I hit the button "Register gateway".
And here we go.
We're done with the Gateway Registration part.
Okay, so we're done with the second step.
So now we need to register an end-device on the Network Server.
That is the third step. From the console,
we go on the "Applications" section, we create an application training-usmb and we validate. In this application,
I'm going to manually register an OTAA end-device.
So in my application, I click on "Register end-device", I select the frequency plan and the LoRaWAN version.
And I provide the AppEUI/JoinEUI.
I use zero as I'm not using a Join Server.
Then as usual I provide my DevEUI and I generate an AppKey.
This is the same parameters that I will set up in my device.
And to finish the process I click on "Register end-device".
Great.
So now the last step is the device configuration.
I just need to configure my end-device with the OTAA activation mode.
The same DevEUI, the same AppKey and the same JoinEUI/AppEUI.
And when it's done, I start my end-device.
If we go in the live data section.
We can see the frames decrypted in the Application Server.
Excellent.
Our LoRaWAN Server works perfectly.
Again, we were a bit fast for this last demonstration because we've done it before with many more details.
So if you want more information, go back in the corresponding video we did with the Thing Network,
that's exactly the same process.
There might be some tiny changes because obviously this is a continuously improving project, but the
idea remains the same.
Please give it a try and tell us if you've managed to do it.